All my friends and welcome to exercise number 67, we are asked to insert notes in circular link at
lest we, by the way, we are going to push then notes, so we are going to insert notes at the beginning
of the list.
OK, so how to do that?
We have solved and we have seen this in their lectures before with animation and we have it with about
this topic and we have solved this exercise in see?
Now let's create a method here public.
No public static and note that you don't know because we are going to insert it as no and at have a
reference we need to to get the head of the list because we are going to insert the note before this
verdict for us before to the head.
OK, now what are the what is the data that we are going to put it is of type empty and cold data?
OK, now
node node one equal to new node, we are creating the node.
We are creating another 10 party nodes that they refer to the headdress and we start by putting the
data.
So creating the nodes here, one first step creating creating nodes.
The second step is.
Creating data or creating.
Let me insert inserting data.
We can make them because it is connected with and that therefore that creating nodes step, it's the
same.
So it's not the big difference because we are creating the nodes, we have created the reference and
we are inserting the data inside it.
OK, now node one dot next equal to reference.
You see, guys, what we have done, what we have done here.
Consider a circle link, at least here a b.
A. We are referencing them, and C refers to that to the first.
We are going to insert a new note here.
It is called containing the ETA e but goes there.
We have it created there that the data of type and I am talking about linked list of type car.
It's the same concept.
What?
I can change them here in order not to be confused, just to talk about me, that I am creating integers
and I am putting car.
No guys.
So I am going to insert in your note and the first here at the beginning.
So what I need to do, I need to remove this link and point it to here.
So three now points to Ford, OK, guys, and I need to create this link that points Ford to the one
but one there is a pointer here called had that point, it was pointing to the head of one.
So for that, I have created a note one.
This is the note.
I have put the data inside it I have asked for and I pressed the head reference, which is the head,
which was one.
So I have created it temp here.
So temp refers to one.
Now we need to move node one the next equal to had the ref.
So we have created by this step this reference.
So Ford now refers to one as its next and that data we have created for and everything.
Works fine.
Now we need to find and to make this link that is from the end to the first how to do it.
OK, we need to link three by the four.
OK, let's see how to make.
Now we need to make that reference from the last note to that first flight because it is a circular
list, OK?
Creating the links.
If you had reference that's not equal to null, then make a while loop that goes through and check if
the link is not null, then set the next of the last.
No.
OK, because we are going to make the move, we need to set the last note to become the first go to
point to the first.
OK.
It's very simple.
So how to do that had the reference does not equal to and then the next we use them equal to them to
the next.
And that we exist from them that next week while no one else, we point the.
Here we point health
nodes one the next equal to note that, OK.
It's very simple.
No.
Had the reference equal to no one and the return note and no reference which is better goes we have
inserted the node one at the beginning and now it becomes the hat.
So what we have done, creating the nodes, inserting the data inside, and we have created a temporary
variable that is pointing to the head and we have moved that cursor until the temp until reaching the
end.
So at the end, when reaching the end, the last node make the temp the next, which is the last node
equal to node one that we have created and newly created.
And we return that defense.
OK.
It's very simple.
Let's try to see this test this method, by the way, this method will cost us all of and because we
are traversing all the elements inside the list.
So this would cost us time complexity.
Oh, can.
OK.
No.
Go to the main
we insert, we start by.
We have great static.
Yes.
So push method.
I need to push one.
Which is to have had the reference had
I need to make a reference above.
And they create a note here called had.
Okay, so I need to make a hand.
You can make it above or you can make it into initialized list as empty so
as and
how to do that by making a note have equal to no.
OK.
It's very simple now we are going to create to create a link, at least circle a link at least would
be like one two three four.
How to do that?
We start by making had equal to bush because Bush, where it took him to perimeter note and the data
and returns note.
So I need to store it inside a variable of type.
No had.
And I put one.
For sure, had the bush of had and City again have equal to Bush had and two had equal Bush had and
one system ducked out the rent and contents of circular link and less how to make it.
We have created in the previous exercise a method called print list, so I will use it to print the
list.
How to do it?
I will call.
It directly, and I passed the first note as it's the head of it and start printing from starting from
this one.
OK.
I have done this, so I need to run circulars and get this.
And the content of circular link at least one, two, three and four.
You see guys one using push.
We are pushing elements after that or before their hat.
So if I push here had and ninety nine, so it would be before no one.
OK, I'm not.
I'm not adding the elements at the end.
We will see it in later exercises.
We are pushing the new new nodes at the beginning of the list.
So this is our list.
This is how we create and push elements at the end at the first of that list and how we print that list.
OK.